peter sankiewicz

senior software engineer

https://github.com/petsan https://www.linkedin.com/in/petsan

20+ years of proven experience designing, implementing and testing complex software solutions for new products. Dedicated to elegance and quality in code. Accomplished coder, team player, excellent communicator, creative problem-solver, experienced leader. Organized, self-motivated, and passionate about learning.

psankiewicz@icloud.com

206-849-0434

skill areas

- · Python, Java, JavaScript, Node, Selenium, Git
- · Information Security
- Test Planning, Automation, Analysis
- GCP, Azure, AWS
- · JIRA, TestRails, LiquidPlanner
- Docker, k8s, Concourse CI
- · Agile, Scrum, Kanban
- · RESTful APIs, Clean Architecture TDD
- · Leadership, Project Management
- · Ubuntu, macOS, Windows, iOS, Android.

professional experience

Piorun, Inc.

Software Engineer • 2020 - Present

Full Stack Web Developer / QA Engineer / Consultant / Owner. — Responsible for deploying e-commerce stores.

• Working with several clients to migrate their inventory to selling on-line.

Vulcan, Inc.

Senior Engineer • 2001 - 2019

Software Development Engineer in Test - Responsible for automated testing for an iOS and browser based application to playback video assets.

- Built an automated testing framework based on existing test plans.
- Supported manual QA efforts with automation and test analysis.
- Analized app performance metrics.
- Ensured stability of software releases and acted as the Release Manager.

Lead Quality & AV/IT Engineer — Lead engineer responsible for the quality and performance for a multi-million dollar custom projection location based entertainment project.

- · Produced and executed extensive test plans, test automation and test reports accross a wide range of custom hardware and software.
- Envisioned, designed, and oversaw the production of a custom server to efficiently play back video and video games on four 4K projectors at 80GBps.
- · Produced, converted and assesed 8K-60 video streams, with various encoding and quality settings.
- Participated in multi-day builds of the Holodome, including at TED 2019 in Vancouver B.C..
- Development tools: Python, Unity, Selenium, Windows UWP, iOS, Android
- Program Management tools: JIRA, TestRails, LiquidPlanner, Agile, Scrum

DevOps Tools Engineer — Developed cloud infrastructure automation for global, multi-million dollar Philanthropy projects. Enabled reliable, repeatable deployments to production environments on multiple cloud providers.

- Implemented Kubernetes deployments for containerized applications in the cloud.
- Built continuous integration/continuous deployment pipelines on Concourse CI.
- Built cloud-agnostic tooling to automate infrastructure provisioning.
- Development tools: Python, Docker, Kubernetes, Google Cloud Platform, Azure Cloud, AWS, Concourse CI, Pair-Programming

Software Engineer - Full-stack web devloper on a cross-platform web application.

- · Performed feature engineering.
- Development tools: Django, JavaScript, JQuery, PostrgreSQL, node.js, angular.js.
- · Co-ordinated with other engineers to ensure software stability.

Lead Quality Engineer - Led the quality efforts for the Wildlife Conservation Initiatives for the \$100M Vulcan Philanthropy group.

- · Successfully engaged with multiple stakeholders on the value of quality engineering practices.
- · Implemented team-wide initiatives for learning.
- Successfully released multiple products across multiple release launches.
- Thoroughly debugged issues found before submitting tickets.
- Led the team in Scrum implementation.

Lead Quality Engineer — Led the testing efforts on multiple world-wide deployments.

- Release management of multiple simultanous products across a world-wide collection of properties.
- · Participated in the initial installation and led the testing effort of AV hardware on the MY Octopus Mega-Yacht.
- · Reported on testing efforts to stakeholders.

Microsoft, Inc. (Contractor)

Lead Quality Engineer • 1997 - 2001

Windows NT Site Server — Responsible for creating, updating, and executing automated test scripts across multiple servers in a laboratory setting.

- · Designed and executed automated test cases.
- · Focused on testing TCP/IP and LDAP.
- Reported on testing results.

Windows 98 - Led a team of Quality Engineers.

- Led a team of QA Engineers in structured testing methodologies, verification and reporting.
- Designed and executed test plans of the Windows 98 network stack.
- Designed and executed test plans for Windows 98 internationalized in German.

Keane, Inc.

Windows 95 Support Engineer • 1995 - 1997

Phone Support Engineer II

- Troubleshot support calls not solved by first queue.
- Focused on the Windows 95 networking stack.
- Entered bugs into Microsoft's bug database when encountered.

Phone Support Engineer I

- Troublshot support calls from end-users.
- Entered call logs into the database.
- · Transferred calls to next queue when necessary.

River Riders, Inc.

Whitewater Rafting Guide • 2002 - 2007

Guided whitewater rafting crews.

- Safely guided whitewater rafts crews down the Wenatchee river.
- · Prepared lunch for guests and crew.
- · Maintained rafts and other equipment.

education

Capella University

BS, IT — Information Assurance & Security • Magna Cum Laude • 2010-2015

University of Washington

BS, Pre-Med (1994 –)

Code Fellows

Full stack web development bootcamp

tech community

- Holodome at TED in Vancouver, 2019
- StarWest Conference
- Application Lifecycle Management Conference
- Attended other conferences

projects

- Media Systems similar to TIVO and Netflix (Mobile/Web)
- Holodome (holodome360.com) (Windows, Unity)
- DevOps cloud management tool for internal projects (GCP, Azure, AWS)(BASH/Python)
- Allen Coral Atlas (allencoralatlas.org) (Mobile/Web)
- Maritime monitoring (skylight.global) (Web)
- Species conservation (earthranger.com) (Mobile/Web)
- Global fishery mapping (seaaroundus.org) (Web)
- Great Elephant Census (greatelephantcensus.com) (Android)
- XBMC Touch (http://xbmctouch.com/), (iOS)
- Brain Atlas (brain-map.org/) (Web)
- The EMP Museum (empmuseum.org/) (Windows)
- Fayve (en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fayve) (iOS)
- Flying Heritage (flyingheritage.com) (Web)
- Project Halo (allenai.org) (Web)
- Racing Extinction (RacingExtinction.com) (Web)
- MS Outlook extension (xiant.com)
- Yopp similar to Facebook (Windows App)
- Tackle Ebola (http://www.tackleebola.org/) (Web)